# Pierre Le Nestour

# Software engineer

#### **ABOUT ME**

Full stack developer with a lot of experience with a different range of technologies. I have led teams designing and building innovative solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals.

During the last years, I have focused on the stack React / Typescript / Node.js / Python.

I am curious, autonomous and value engagement and honesty.

+44 (0)7774 176010 twogrouptheory@gmail.com https://github.com/k3roulas Brighton, UK

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Javascript / Typescript / React / Node.js GraphQL / Redis / Postgres

Docker / AWS (ECS - EC2 - lambda)

Python / Django / Django CMS / Django Rest Framework / SQL Alchemy

PHP / Symfony / Laravel

Agile / Scrum / Atlassian suite

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Entertainment Partners,** Remote contract — *Full stack developer*

December 2022 - September 2023 (10 months)

Joined a SCRUM team to help to implement the new rules defined by the negotiation with the union of the entertainment industry (TV/Film). Their product consists of a production finance solution built with Python, with the not so famous TurgoGears framework, a more classic front end with React / Typescript, and few calls to AWS lambda functions.

Python / Celery / Postgres / SQL Alchemy / AWS lambda / Typescript / React

# **LEO Learning,** Brighton — Lead developer

July 2016 – October 2022 (6 years and 3 months)

LEO learning provides e-learning content and services. I worked on the frontend and backend side of multiple projects, at first as a lead developer then as a software engineering team lead.

My responsibilities:

- Estimates
- Technical solution design
- Code and lead the dev team
- Conduct the reviews
- Promote good practices
- Solve technical issues
- Hands on the AWS console
- Continuous integration and deployment (pipelines to ECS and EC2)
- Design and implementation of authentication mechanism (Oauth / OIDC / SAML)
- Support non technical teams (PM/QA)

Some of the projects I have led:

### **BP** - The Learning Campus

Ecosystem of e-learning products unified into a single experience by the development of a React SPA.

• Design and implementation of GraphQL client and server

- Development of authentication with OIDC and federated identities from Salesforce to Cognito
- Definition of cache policy client and server side
- Creation of React components

Typescript / React / MUI / Express / GraphQL / OIDC / jest Team of 4 devs

# BP - User Management Platform

Creation of a specific tool to provision users accounts in multiple SaaS platforms (Salesforce. Cognito and 5 other applications).

Websocket with PubSub over GraphQL / React / Typescript / MUI / Redis / Rsmq / jest

## American Institute of Certified Public Accountants

Development of a tool (LTI) for an existing LMS (Learning Management System) to enhance its capabilities.

- Development of the React application
- GraphQL client and server implementation
- Design and implementation of the database data model
- Add lambda functions triggered by EventBridge (AWS)

Typescript / React / MUI / Sequilize / GraphQL / lambda / PostgreSQL / BullMQ / jest Team of 3 devs

## **ThermoFisher**

Creation of a learning management system with two components:

- Moodle application : used as a backend for the Laravel application.
- Laravel application : surface and enhance content from Moodle

PHP / Laravel / docker / EC2 / TNTSearch / Crystal - PHP API Wrapper Team of 3 devs

# <u>Deloitte - https://www.deloitteifrslearning.com</u>

Django CMS site for Deloitte to provide the elearning IFRS content to the public. The project has been developed, tested, reviewed, deployed and delivered in 10 days. (team of 2 devs)

**Django CMS** / postgres / Whoosh / pytest

## World Athletics - Olympics

E-learning platform for officials, athletes and fans.

I have led a team of 4 developers on the creation of the three layers of the ecosystem:

- front: React / Express / GraphQL / Bootstrap horizontally scalable (AWS ECS)
- middleware: Python / Django / DRF horizontally scalable (AWS ECS) with cache policies to protect Moodle
- Learning Management System: Moodle / PHP

## Visa International

To gamify the learning of VISA products, we created a highly interactive React based SCORM application.

# React / SCORM / Redux / Cornerstone / jest Team of 3 devs

### Fidelity International

- Creation of a scheduler to awards badges to learner
- Creation of a portal to expose e-learning content

### **Django CMS** / Kroniker / Bootstrap

#### Moodle development

- Creation and maintenance of multiple sites (PHP / PHPUnit)
- In-house Moodle multi-tenant solution with *Elasticsearch* record store.

# **22 point six**, Burgess Hill — Senior developer

January 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 6 months)

Technology start-up focused on web solutions.

- Creation of an in-house CMS based on CMF project
- Deployment and enhancement of the solution for clients

Symfony / PHP / PHPUnit

# **BDM Voice**, Haywards Heath — Senior developer

July 2013 – December 2015 (2 years 6 months)

Small team of two developers working agile from design to market of a large range of products.

In charge of all the tasks from the development to managing the infrastructure (Digital Ocean) or DevOps tasks (security/deployment).

I worked on a variety of products, bringing modernisation to improve maintenance and resilience to change, in particular:

- Moved legacy code to Symfony/Doctrine following modern standards (PSR)
- Covered the code with functional and unit test

Design and development of a platform to analyze call centre efficiency.

AngularJS / Symfony / PHP/ PHPUnit / Behat / Doctrine / DevOps

## **Previous Role**, France

- **Technical project management support** SFR (Vodafone group), Paris. Tech advisor on payment solutions coordinating dev teams in India and Germany.
- Technical application management support RTE (EDF group), Paris,
- Developer EDF, Paris C++ low latency solution for the national electric grid
- Developer CEA, Paris C/C++ for industrial tools

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, French (native)

#### **EDUCATION**

MSc Computer Science, Paris XIII University, France